up.com 2017-05-19

# UP: Website Privacy Policy

  * Home
  * About Us
  * Corporate Information

### Our Commitment to Privacy

Your privacy is important to us and UP is committed to maintaining your confidence and trust. For that reason, we have established this Privacy Policy. To make our policy easy to find, we make it accessible from every page of our site.

Any personal information provided by customers/visitors to the Union Pacific Railroad website is used for internal purposes only. Union Pacific does not plan to sell or lease any personal information, customer listings, or aggregate data gathered through the UP site to any outside party. Nor does Union Pacific plan to divulge personal information or customer information gathered through its website to anyone but Union Pacific, its affiliates, and suppliers assisting Union Pacific. 

### Information Collected and How We Use It

In general, you can visit our website without telling us who you are, or revealing personal information about yourself. However, customers and other users can, if they choose, participate in additional secured applications. Additionally, Union Pacific may use cookies, tracking pixels, and IP addresses to collect information regarding use of Union Pacific websites.

We collect the following information about visitors:

 **Personal and company information** , which you have voluntarily submitted to us (such as name, address, telephone number, email address, social security numbers, credit card numbers, or credit information) to register for secure applications such as MyUPRR, the Bidder's List registration, the up.jobs site, or through email or other communication with our offices. We may, from time to time, send information to registered users about system changes or new applications that we think may be of interest. Social Security Numbers submitted to us as part of an employment application are transmitted in an encrypted format. This information is not used outside of UP for any purpose other than that for which it was originally intended.

 **Aggregate information** , or automatically collected non-identifying statistics (such as information about how many visitors log on to our sites, the pages they access, etc.).

 **Information regarding the use of Union Pacific’s website** , which is used to enhance our services, to better meet the needs and preferences of our customers and other visitors, and to enhance the security of the UP site. Our web servers collect the IP addresses of visitors, but not the email addresses. Additionally, Union Pacific may use cookie and tracking pixels, as described below.

### Cookies & Tracking Pixels

A cookie is a very small text file that a Web page server sends to your hard drive, in response to your browser's request for a Web page. The purpose of the cookie is to help a website server recognize a user. Sites with secured information use cookies to help recognize User IDs, or on our site, to help users navigate between secured and unsecured information. Cookies also help website managers track which information on their site is most useful and most often accessed, and which pages are seldom visited. The cookie for our site, recognizable only to our server, simply helps to identify you and tell us which information you wish to read, and which you don't. To the extent permitted by your browser, you may opt out of cookie tracking.

Occasionally, Union Pacific also collects information related to the effectiveness of our digital advertisements. Specifically, Union Pacific works with third-party companies that use tracking technologies (tracking pixels) on our website in order to serve interest-based ads on our behalf across the internet. These companies may collect information about your activity on our sites and your interaction with our advertising and use this information to determine which ads you see on third-party websites and applications. For more information about this practice and to understand your options including how to opt out of receiving these tailored advertisements, please visit [http://www.aboutads.info](http://www.aboutads.info/).

### Do Not Track Policy

Do Not Track is a privacy preference that users may set in their web browsers. When a user turns on the Do Not Track signal, the browser sends a message to websites requesting them not to track the user. At this time, we do not respond to Do Not Track browser settings or signals. For information about Do Not Track, please visit: [www.allaboutdnt.org](http://www.allaboutdnt.org/).

### Registered User Access

Customers who have registered to access secured information and applications agree to abide by the confidentiality guidelines and policies of UP's Website Security Policy.

### Links to Other Sites

UP provides links to its parent company, the Union Pacific Corporation, as well as its [subsidiaries](http://www.uprr.com/aboutup/info/up-sites.shtml). We also link to a number of third-party external sites. The inclusion of any link does not imply UP endorsement of the external site company, its website, or the products and services it promotes or sells. When you leave the UP site to visit one of these linked sites, the only information transferred to the third party is the fact that you came from UP.com (the "refer address").

UP is not responsible or liable for the independent privacy policies of these third party sites. You should consult the privacy policies at these sites to determine how your information may be used. 

### Data Security

UP is committed to online data security, and for that reason we take steps to make all information received from you online as secure as reasonably possible from unauthorized access and use. Union Pacific policy prohibits the sharing of User IDs or passwords.

### Changing or Correcting Your Information

Registered users of MyUPRR can access the personally identifiable information that we collect online and maintain, by clicking on the Customer link under "My Profile" at MyUPRR. To protect your privacy and security, we will take reasonable steps to verify your identity before granting access or making changes.

Inquiries submitted via "Feedback," sent via email, or sent using the Webmaster link, are processed and responded to as soon as possible. If there is a need to access or update a past email, please direct inquiries to the [webmaster@up.com](http://www.up.com/up/forms/feedback/)

Applicants who wish to amend information submitted with a job application, or Suppliers needing to change Bidder's Registration information, may direct inquiries to the [webmaster@up.com](http://www.up.com/up/forms/feedback/). 

### Children's Privacy

While we do not direct any of the information on our site specifically to children, we are very proud of our History pages and the information they provide for students and railfans alike. We believe that protecting the privacy of the very young is especially important, and for that reason it is our intention to never collect or maintain information from children on our website.

### Contact Us

Should you have other questions or concerns about this Privacy Policy, please contact the webmaster@up.com

Effective Date: March 2016
